{"Topic": "Freedom Struggle", "Subject": "General Knowledge", "Data": [{"Question": "The idea of Pakistan was first conceived by", "op1": "Muhammad Iqbal", "op2": "M. A. Jinnah", "op3": "Shaukar Ali", "op4": "Aga Khan", "Answer": 4}, {"Question": "Mappila rebellion is associated with which of the following states?", "op1": "Bihar", "op2": "Gujarat", "op3": "Punjab", "op4": "Kerala", "Answer": 3}, {"Question": "Kuka Movement is associated with which of the following states?", "op1": "Assam", "op2": "Bengal", "op3": "Punjab", "op4": "Maharashtra", "Answer": 2}, {"Question": "Which of the following movements immediately followed the partition of Bengal?", "op1": "Non-cooperation Movement", "op2": "Swadeshi Movement", "op3": "Civil Disobedience Movement", "op4": "Ghadar Movement", "Answer": 2}, {"Question": "The Rowlatt Act was passed in the year", "op1": "1917", "op2": "1919", "op3": "1921", "op4": "1923", "Answer": 2}, {"Question": "Who was the first Indian native ruler to accept the system of Subsidiary Alliance?", "op1": "Scindia of Gwalior", "op2": "Nizam of Hyderabad", "op3": "Dalip Singh of Punjab", "op4": "Gaikwad of Baroda", "Answer": 2}, {"Question": "With reference to the Indian freedom struggle, which one of the following is the correct chronological order of the given events?", "op1": "Partition of Bengal - Lucknow Pact - Surat split of congress", "op2": "Partition of Bengal - Surat split of congress - Lucknow Pact", "op3": "Surat split of Congress - Partition of Bengal - Lucknow Pact", "op4": "Surat split of congress - Lucknow Pact - Partition of Bengal"}, {"Question": "Who said The Simon Commission Report should be thrown on a heap of rubbish?", "op1": "Mahatma Gandhi", "op2": "Shivaswami Ayyar", "op3": "Mohammad Ali jinnah", "op4": "Jawaharlal Nehru", "Answer": 2}, {"Question": "Which day was declared as the Direct Action Day by the Muslim League?", "op1": "3rd September 1946", "op2": "16th August 1946", "op3": "16th May 1946", "op4": "4th December 1946", "Answer": 3}, {"Question": "For which community were seats reserved by the Morley-Minto reforms?", "op1": "Jews", "op2": "Muslims", "op3": "Christians", "op4": "Sikhs", "Answer": 2}, {"Question": "Who among the following Europeans were the last to come to pre-independence India as traders?", "op1": "Dutch", "op2": "English", "op3": "French", "op4": "Portuguese", "Answer": 2}, {"Question": "Which one of the following aroused a wave of popular indignation that led to the massacre by the British at Jallianwala Bagh?", "op1": "The Arms Act", "op2": "The Public Safety Act", "op3": "The Rowlatt Act", "op4": "The Vernacular Press Act", "Answer": 3}, {"Question": "The Simon Commission was boycotted by the Indians because -", "op1": "it sought to curb civil liberties of the Indians", "op2": "it proposed to partition India", "op3": "it was an all-white commission without Indian representation", "op4": "it proposed measures to contain nationalism", "Answer": 3}, {"Question": "Which one of the following was the first fort constructed by the British in India?", "op1": "Fort William", "op2": "Fort St. George", "op3": "Fort St. David", "op4": "Fort St. Angelo", "Answer": 3}, {"Question": "When did Governor-General\u2019s rule end in India?", "op1": "15th August 1947", "op2": "9th August 1948", "op3": "26th January 1950", "op4": "2nd October 1950", "Answer": 2}, {"Question": "6th April, 1930 is well known in the history of India because this date is associated with -", "op1": "Dandi March by Mahatma", "op2": "Quit India Movement", "op3": "Partition of Bengal", "op4": "Partition of India", "Answer": 3}, {"Question": "The first attempt to introduce a representative and popular element in the governance of India was made through -", "op1": "Indian Council Act, 1861", "op2": "Indian Council Act, 1892", "op3": "Indian Council Act, 1909", "op4": "Government of India Act, 1919", "Answer": 1}, {"Question": "The system of communal electorate in India was first introduced by the -", "op1": "Indian Council Act of 1892", "op2": "Minto-Morley Reforms of 1909", "op3": "Montagu-Chelmsford Reforms of 1919", "op4": "Government of India Act of 1935", "Answer": 3}, {"Question": "In which year was English recommended as the medium of instruction for higher education in India by Lord Macaulay?", "op1": "1835", "op2": "1833", "op3": "1858", "op4": "1821", "Answer": 2}, {"Question": "Which battle established the supremacy of the British rule in India?", "op1": "Battle of Plassey, 1757", "op2": "Battle of Buxar, 1764", "op3": "3rd Mysore war, 1790-92", "op4": "4th Mysore war 1799", "Answer": 1}, {"Question": "With which of the following is the comment \u2018no vakil, no appeal, no dalil\u2019 associated?", "op1": "The Communal Award, 1932", "op2": "The Simon Commission, 1928", "op3": "The Rowlatt Act, 1919", "op4": "The Vemacular Press Act, 1878", "Answer": 2}, {"Question": "The Muslim League demanded a separate state for the Muslims in the year :", "op1": "1920", "op2": "1930", "op3": "1940", "op4": "1946"}, {"Question": "Mumbai was taken by the English East India company from :", "op1": "The Portuguese", "op2": "The Dutch", "op3": "Charles 1", "op4": "Charles 2", "Answer": 3}, {"Question": "Swadeshi Movement started in India during :", "op1": "The Champaran Satyagrah of Gandhi", "op2": "Anti-Bengal Partition agitation", "op3": "The protest against Rowlatt Act", "op4": "The first non-co-operation movement of 1919-22", "Answer": 3}, {"Question": "Which of the following was NOT the outcome of Jallianwala Bagh massacre?", "op1": "Renunciation of the British titles and positions by many Indians", "op2": "Change in Gandhiji\u2019s attitude towards the British Government", "op3": "Temporary peace in Punjab", "op4": "Suspension of Gen. Dyer from service", "Answer": 3}, {"Question": "\u2018Khilafat Movement\u2019 subsided because of :", "op1": "the understanding reached between the Congress and the Muslim league", "op2": "the concessions given to Muslims by the British", "op3": "accession of Kemal Pasha to the throne of Turkey", "op4": "none of the above reasons", "Answer": 3}, {"Question": "Which party was in power in the U. K. when India became independent?", "op1": "liberal", "op2": "Conservative", "op3": "Labour", "op4": "No party, since a National Government was in power there", "Answer": 2}, {"Question": "The interim Government at the centre was formed in 1946 :", "op1": "before the visit of the Cabinet Mission", "op2": "after the visit of the Cabinet Mission", "op3": "as a result of Cripps Mission", "op4": "after Mountbatten came to India for transfer of power to Indians", "Answer": 2}, {"Question": "Who was the Prime Minister of U. K. at the time of India\u2019s independence?", "op1": "Winston Churchill", "op2": "Clement Attlee", "op3": "Lord Mountbatten", "op4": "Ramsay Mac Donald", "Answer": 4}, {"Question": "The Khilafat Movement was started by :", "op1": "Muhmmad Ali Jinnah", "op2": "Dr. Zakir Hussain", "op3": "Fakhruddin Ali Ahmed", "op4": "Ali Brothers", "Answer": 3}, {"Question": "The provision for separate electorate for Hindus and Muslims was made in :", "op1": "Government of India Act, 1935", "op2": "Montague Chelmsford reforms", "op3": "Minto-Morley reforms", "op4": "Mountbatten Plan", "Answer": 4}, {"Question": "The British introduced provincial autonomy in India through :", "op1": "The Minto-Morley Reforms Act of 1909", "op2": "The Montagu-Chelmsford Reforms of 1919", "op3": "Indian Councils Act of 1892", "op4": "The Government of India Act 1935", "Answer": 1}, {"Question": "The famous Pakistan resolution was passed at :", "op1": "Lahore", "op2": "Delhi", "op3": "Bombay", "op4": "Lucknow"}, {"Question": "In which session did the Indian National Congress declare Poorna Swaraj (Complete Independence) to be its goal?", "op1": "Lahore, 1929", "op2": "Lucknow, 1916", "op3": "Tripuri, 1939", "op4": "Lahore, 1940", "Answer": 1}, {"Question": "Which important event immediately preceded the Jallianwala Bagh massacre?", "op1": "Communal Award", "op2": "Arrival of Simon Commission", "op3": "Non-Co-operation Movement", "op4": "Rowlatt Act enactment", "Answer": 4}, {"Question": "The Hunter Commission was appointed by the British to probe the :", "op1": "Chauri-Chaura incident", "op2": "Jallianwala Bagh tragedy", "op3": "Khilafat Movement", "op4": "Non-Co-operation Movement", "Answer": 2}, {"Question": "Who once remarked, \"Nehru is a patriot while Jinnah is a politician?\"", "op1": "Maulana Azad", "op2": "Mahatma Gandhi", "op3": "Sir Mohammed Iqbal", "op4": "Abdul Gaffar Khan"}, {"Question": "Which act was known as \u2018Black-Bill\u2019?", "op1": "Rowlatt Act", "op2": "Pitt\u2019s India Act", "op3": "The Regulating Act", "op4": "Indian Council Act", "Answer": 3}, {"Question": "ated pages"}, {"Question": "s on British Governor Generals"}, {"Question": "s on First War of Indian Independence"}, {"Question": "s on Places during Freedom Struggle"}, {"Question": "s on Indian Revolutionaries"}, {"Question": "- British Governor Generals"}]}